我们已经谈了一些人类视觉系统。我们来看看一些方式
We have talked a bit about the human visual system. Let’s have a look at the way some
其他动物做到了。考虑一下蜜蜂的情况。蜜蜂是一个
other animals do it. Consider the case of the bee. The bee is a
非常小的动物，因此它有一个非常小的大脑。蜜蜂的大脑很重
very small animal and therefore it has got a very small brain. The bee’s brain weighs
只有一克，它只有10^6个神经元。因此，与人类大脑形成鲜明对比
just one gram and it has only got 10^6 neurons. So contrast that with the human brain, which
有一个半公斤的灰质和10^11个神经元。蜜蜂的脑子要小得多，
has got one and a half kilograms of grey matter and 10^11 neurons. The bee brain is much smaller,
更简单，但它仍然能够完成基于信息的非常复杂的任务
much simpler, yet it is still able to do very complex tasks based simply on the information
来自它的眼睛。现在我们有两只眼睛，蜜蜂有两只眼睛。
that comes from its eyes. Now we have two eyes and the bee has two eyes.
没有什么可以说所有的动物都必须有两只眼睛。所以这是一个接近
There is nothing that says that all animals have to have two eyes. So this is a close
一只蜘蛛，这只特殊的蜘蛛有四只眼睛，我觉得有一些
up of a spider and this particular spider has got four eyes and I think there are some
有五只眼睛的蜘蛛。因此，进化已经出现了许多不同的设计
spiders that have got five eyes. So evolution has come up with many different designs of
眼睛本身和眼睛的配置，明显赋予一些特殊的优势
eyes themselves, and configurations of eyes, that clearly confer some particular advantage
对携带它们的有机体。这是近距离拍摄的眼睛
to the organism that is carrying them. Here is a close up photograph of the eyes
一只昆虫这些是复眼，由多个多边形面组成。
of an insect. These are compound eyes, made up of a number of polygonal facets.
这是另一种复眼。这个没有相当的视野
Here is another type of compound eye. This one doesn’t have quite the field of view
我们刚才看到的那个。这是鹦鹉螺的眼睛，这是相当的
of the one we just looked at. Here is the eye of a nautilus, which is quite
原始的远洋动物。而眼睛真的是一个非常简单的针孔相机;它
a primitive ocean-going animal. And the eye really is a very simple pinhole camera; it
没有这样的镜头。这是扇贝的眼睛。所以蓝色
doesn’t have a lens as such. Here are the eyes of a scallop. So the blue
你可以看到的物体，每一个都是一个非常简单的眼睛，它有很多
objects that you can see, each of those is a very simple eye and it has got a large number
他们周围的东西实际上是它的嘴巴。这些眼睛中的每一个都有点像
of them around the outside of what is effectively its mouth. Each of these eyes is a bit like
反射望远镜。那些蓝色物体的内部非常有光泽，因此传入
a reflecting telescope. The inside of those blue objects is quite shiny and so incoming
光线不是通过镜头折射而是从内部的光泽表面反射出来
light rays, instead of refracting in through a lens, reflect off the shiny surface inside
那只眼睛落在光感受器上。所以这个扇贝，它反而使用反射
that eye and fall onto the photoreceptors. So this scallop, it uses reflection rather
然后屈光，它有很多眼睛。
then refraction and it has got a very large number of eyes.
这是鱿鱼的眼睛，它像我们一样拥有一只眼睛，它已经进化了
This is the eye of a squid and it has got a lensed eye like we have, and it has evolved
完全独立于我们拥有的眼睛。
completely independently of the lensed eye that we have.
这是一只鸟的眼睛的近距离。昆虫中的复眼含有一种
And here is a close up of the eyes of a bird. The compound eye in the insect contains a
小平面数;个别光感应元素称为ommatidia，如果我们看一下
number of facets; individual light sensing elements called ommatidia and if we look at
它是欧亚大陆的一个横截面，它有效地在顶部有一个镜头，它可以任何漏斗
a cross-section of the ommatidia it has got effectively a lens on top which funnels any
落在这个含有光敏化学物质的锥形细胞内的光线，
light that falls on it down inside this conical cell which contains the light sensitive chemicals,
当光落在它上面时会发出神经脉冲。所以每一个都是有效的
which emit a neural pulse when light falls on it. So each one of these is effectively
单像素相机，或者我们可以用这些术语来思考它。我们有一个完整的阵列
a single pixel camera, or we can think of it in those terms. And we have a whole array
他们指向略微不同的方向，这使得昆虫可以创造一个公平的
of them pointing in slightly different directions and that allows the insect to create a fairly
大视野。
large field of view.